[ woman on TV ] We have breaking news .
It happened just a few moments ago apparently .
We have very little information available .
[ man ] We have , I understand , an eyewitness on the phone right now .
Rog .
[ TV continues , indistinct ]
[ woman ] ... in the middle of the plaza at 8 : 52 .
With limited information at this point ,
we don 't know about injuries in the building ...
[ Lee ] What the hell happened ?
A bomb .
I think .
So sad .
- [ man ] There was a loud sound ... - Rog , I got to , uh ...
I can only describe it as , it sounded like a missile , not an airplane .
Then there was a loud explosion and ...
[ birds chirping ]
[ panting ]
[ bell rings , crowd cheers ]
Wanna go higher ?
[ imitates explosion ]
- [ applause , cheers ] - [ woman ] You got it !
[ cheering ]
[ man ] Let it in there !
[ man on radio ] So , the Red Sox with two down on a base hit .
- First time through the order ? - Third .
Third ?
- What inning is this ? - Fifth .
Oh , boy .
[ chattering ]
Your hands are ... disgusting .
Let me do it .
Disgusting ?
[ chuckles ] Wow .
[ applause , cheers ]
Just breathe .
[ man on radio ] He pops that one up down the line .
That 's ducking in ! It falls in !
- What 's the inning of that game ? - Third .
- Let 's go ! - Oh !
Come on , Henry !
You got it , you got it !
Dive , dive , dive !
- [ umpire ] He 's out ! - Ooh !
Hey , how do you say " dive " ?
- Dive ? - It 's a tough one .
[ chuckles ]
[ man ] We 'll take third ball now .
Let 's do it . Whoo !
[ shouting , indistinct ]
Come on .
- [ boy ] Go Marcus ! - [ man 1 ] Here we go . Nice little hit . Here we go .
[ man 2 ] Whoo !
- [ umpire ] Ball ! - [ applause , cheers ]
[ man ] That 's okay . Good eye , good eye !
Alright , Marcus . Wait for your pitch , buddy .
[ man on radio ] This damage with two outs ...
- [ static ] - Shit .
Shit .
[ static continues ]
[ umpire ] Strike one !
[ Lee ] It 's alright .
It 's alright .
[ man ] Goddamn thing .
[ howls ]
[ dog barking ]
Strike two !
[ rumbling ]
[ explosion , rumbling ]
[ chattering ]
Come on . Let 's go .
[ man 1 ] Alright , folks . That 's the game .
Why don 't we all head to our cars .
- [ man 2 ] Okay , let 's go . - [ woman ] Molly !
- Hey . - Hey .
- What was that ? - I don 't know .
- I don 't know what that was . - I 'm gonna take the kids home , okay ?
Okay , yeah . My truck 's up on Main Street .
Okay . Alright , everybody in . Let 's go .
I 'll go with Dad .
Okay . Straight home . Lee ? Lee ?
[ rumbling continues ]
[ horn honks ]
- Hey . You alright ? - Yeah , good .
Your brother say anything going on at the base ?
Not that I know of . He just called . Let me call him back .
Alright . Yeah , let me know .
[ barking ]
My truck 's up there .
[ horn honks ]
- [ siren wailing ] - [ sighs ]
Don 't worry .
Wait here .
[ door closes ]
Ronnie , what do we got ?
We got units headed out there now , EMS and fire .
- Whereabouts ? - I think out by Walker 's farm .
[ screaming ]
[ muted audio ]
What 's wrong ?
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ static ]
[ Evelyn ] It 's okay , honey . It 's okay , honey bunny .
- It 's okay , baby . It 's okay . - [ horn honking ]
- [ Marcus ] Mom ? - Yeah .
What is happening ?
- Oh ! - [ growling ]
[ tires squealing ]
[ screams ] Oh , my God !
- [ horn honking ] - [ panting ]
It 's okay . It 's okay . We 're okay .
- That 's Dad . That 's Dad ! - Where , where , where ?
[ Marcus ] Mom . Mom !
Oh , my God !
[ tires screeching ]
[ tires squealing ]
[ muted audio ]
[ heartbeat thumping faintly ]
[ screaming ]
- You 're okay , baby . - I 'm okay .
It 's okay , honey . It 's okay .
[ creature growling ]
[ panting ]
[ creature clicking ]
[ girl ] I 'm okay .
I 'm okay .
We were on Main Street and , um ... I don 't ...
Are you there ?
- [ static on phone ] - Mom ?
[ creature growls ]
- [ breathing heavily ] - [ growling continues ]
[ man ] Our Father , who art in heaven ,
hallowed be thy name .
Thy kingdom come , thy will be done , on earth as it is in heaven .
Give us this day our daily ...
[ footsteps approaching ]
[ snarling ]
[ muted audio ]
[ heartbeat thumping faintly ]
[ growling continues ]
[ breathing heavily ]
- [ cell phone ringing ] - [ growls ]
[ grunting , screaming ]
[ growls ]
[ footsteps approaching ]
It 's okay . Shh .
[ creature snarling ]
It 's Dad !
[ clicking , growling ]
Down . Get down .
[ growls ]
[ creature growls ]
[ screams ]
[ baby crying ]
Let 's go .
[ crickets chirping ]
[ baby cooing ]
Wait here .
I 'm going back in ...
Stay here .
[ water flowing ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ insects buzzing ]
[ bottles clinking ]
Run !
[ panting ]
[ baby fusses ]
[ groans ]
[ groaning ]
[ screaming ]
- Shh ! - [ muffled screaming ]
Baby , please . Shh !
Baby , please .
- [ panting ] - [ screaming continues ]
No . Please .
[ baby cries ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ woman ] It 's okay , honey . It 's okay .
[ crying ]
It 's okay .
[ screaming ]
[ woman ] It 's okay .
It 's okay .
[ creature growling , clicking ]
[ feedback ]
[ static ]
[ growling ]
- [ groans ] - [ grunts ]
[ creature clicking , growling ]
[ panting ]
[ wood creaking ]
[ creature croaks ]
[ whispering ] Go .
[ creature growling ]
[ growling ]
[ snarling ]
Jump .
[ grunts ]
[ Marcus groaning ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ beeps ]
[ panting ]
[ man ] You can 't stay .
I don 't know why you came all the way up here , but you can 't stay .
Up ?
There 's not enough food ... water . There 's not enough anything .
How do you know we traveled up ?
[ man ] There 's nothing I can do . You won 't survive .
Show me your face .
I can 't help you .
Please , I can 't help you .
Emmett ?
- Emmett ? - [ sighs ]
[ cooing ]
Please .
[ alarm beeping ]
[ alarm stops ]
[ Marcus groaning ]
Breathe , baby .
[ screaming ]
[ footsteps approaching ]
[ alarm beeps , stops ]
[ static ]
How does it work ?
There 's three feet of concrete .
They 'd have to be right above us to hear .
What is it ? Some kind of ...
Some kind of feedback from the microphone ?
It just works . I don 't know .
Just never seen one dead before .
How is he ?
He 's , um ...
Well , it didn 't reach the bone .
But that wrap won 't last .
I 'm sorry .
- For what ? - The boys .
- I assume ... - That day .
And Nora ?
Eleven weeks ago .
She was sick .
Held out as long as we could in the house .
But the pain just ...
It was when she started screaming ...
we had to come here .
That was smart .
It wasn 't enough .
Can I ask you a question ?
When you saw the flame ...
night after night ...
Did you know it was him ?
Yes .
And did you ever think to come for us ?
No .
The people that are left ...
what they 've become ...
You don 't know , do you ?
Well , I do .
They 're not a kind of people worth saving .
[ static continues ]
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ Beyond the sea ♪
What is it ?
[ gasping ]
- What is it ? - Music !
♪ My lover stands On golden sand And watches ... ♪
- It 's ... - " Beyond the Sea . "
- Have you heard this ? - Yes .
No . Dad would 've heard this .
It 's the same song . It 's been playing over and over the last four months .
You 're lying !
My Dad used the radio every day !
- What 's she saying ? - [ Evelyn ] She thinks he would 've heard it .
Who ?
Lee .
It 's the valley .
It 's the valley . I tried the radio from our house too ,
but we never heard anything until we got up here .
Your dad was never gonna make it work .
You 're nothing like him !
Does this mean that there are more people ?
- I don 't know , baby . I don 't . - No !
There 's nothing left .
I told you , there is nothing left .
I want you gone tomorrow .
[ gasps ]
[ panting ]
[ beeps ]
It 's not a song .
On the radio .
Beyond The Sea ... Right ?
It 's not a song ...
It 's a signal .
They 're telling us where to look .
I looked up the radio station .
... where the song is coming from .
It 's an island !
I can follow the train tracks ...
It 's not even one day .
Then I can find a boat .
You can 't do this .
If I can find the song . Where it 's coming from ...
I can use this ...
to change this ...
into this !
Mom , will never ... let you go .
I can save them .
I can save us .
I 'll tell her .
Mom ... I 'll tell her .
Please don 't do this !
I need to try .
Why ?
Because Dad would .
And look what happened to him .
[ breathing heavily ]
[ alarm beeping , stops ]
[ water dripping ]
You have to find her for me .
She 's gone to get help , and I need you to go and find her and bring her back to me .
- Alright , listen to me . - Please , Emmett , I 'm begging you .
- Evelyn ... - I 'm begging you . We were friends .
Emmett , please .
Lee is gone .
Now he 's gone .
It 's a shame .
Because if he were here ...
he 'd look you right in the eye , and he 'd tell you
that his little girl is absolutely the kind of person worth saving .
So please go find her ...
and bring her back to me .
[ crickets chirping ]
[ squawking ]
[ screams ]
[ gasps ]
[ muted audio ]
[ heartbeat thumping faintly ]
[ creature growling ]
- [ feedback ] - [ growling ]
[ squealing ]
[ growling , squealing ]
- [ snarling ] - [ gunshot ]
[ creature growling ]
[ whispering ] Go !
[ clattering , glass breaking ]
[ creature growling , clicking ]
[ clicking continues ]
Alright , listen to me .
We stay here until they 're gone , and then we go .
You understand ?
She can 't hear .
You can 't hear .
Shit !
[ sighs ]
I 'm taking you home . We 'll wait here until they 're gone .
Goddamn it !
Enunciate ... Remember ?
[ sighs ]
I 'm ...
taking you ... back .
[ whispering ] Hey .
They heard ... the shot .
Okay ?
No !
You can 't do this .
Help me .
Enough , please . Enough .
I 'm taking you home !
What home ?
You said ... your wife ...
Hey , don 't ...
Do not ... talk about my wife !
You said
that you could not do enough .
Now you can .
[ cooing ]
[ cooing continues ]
[ muted audio ]
[ panting ]
I found a boat .
Don 't go .
I will be right back .
A matter of hours .
But the baby , I don 't know how ...
I showed you how to do it .
Stay calm .
You have everything you need .
Everything .
Please ...
Look ...
If I don 't go ...
Soon you 'll be in a lot of pain .
And I won 't know
I won 't lose you too .
Breathe ...
Okay ?
I 'll be right back .
[ singing quietly ] ♪ You make me happy ♪
♪ When skies are gray ♪
♪ You 'll never know , dear ♪
♪ How much I love you ♪
♪ So please Don 't take my sunshine away ♪
[ coos ]
I 'll be right back .
[ hissing ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ wood creaking ]
Hey .
It 's okay . It 's okay .
Hey . Look at me .
[ gasps ]
[ creature clicks , growls ]
[ creature growls ]
Hey .
[ Marcus grunting ]
[ creature growls ]
[ panting , grunting ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ lock clicks ]
- [ pounding ] - [ shouts ]
[ clicking ]
[ panting ]
[ hyperventilating ]
[ crying ]
[ creature clicking ]
[ growls ]
[ baby crying ]
[ grunts ]
[ creature clicking ]
[ screaming ]
[ screams ]
[ baby crying ]
[ gasping ]
[ crying ]
Baby . Marcus .
Marcus ! Marcus , wake up !
[ gasps ]
[ gasping ]
[ screaming ]
[ snarls ]
[ creature growls ]
[ clicking , growling ]
[ grunts ]
[ panting ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ chattering , laughing ]
Oh ! Thank you .
You heard the song .
You figured it out .
She did .
- I thought she was ... - Figured it out .
I 'm not sure anyone here can actually believe it .
I think most people had finally given up hope .
Been a long time .
How long ?
That day .
We got here the same way as you .
We were in the city when we heard the hurricane sirens .
Once they knew they couldn 't swim ...
the National Guard were told to start loading people onto boats .
Any boat that they could find .
So as soon as people saw the first one get out safe ...
Well ...
everyone just started pushing forward .
And that 's when they started screaming .
They had 12 boats lined up on the dock that day .
Only two got out .
Anyway , you 're here now .
A new day .
And where are you coming from ?
Ah , just over the Appalachian ridge .
And how long did it take ?
Just under two days .
That 's determination .
It 's necessity .
To get help ?
No .
To give it .
He said he 'll do it .
Yes .
He said yes .
Thank you .
I wanted to say ...
I 'm sorry ...
I doubted you .
I was wrong .
And you were right .
I 'm nothing like him .
You are .
[ sighs ]
[ rattling ]
[ rattling continues ]
Both .
[ chattering ]
Get inside .
Get inside !
[ shouting ]
[ screaming ]
[ horn honking ]
[ honking continues ]
Stay down ! Get down !
[ horn honking ]
Hey , door 's locked . You got a key ?
Where is it ?
We went too fast . What if we lost it ?
Give me the key .
Jesus Christ , it went back !
- No , no , no . - My family .
Alright . Listen to me .
I have to get back to my family .
[ screaming ]
[ electricity crackles ]
[ growls ]
[ panting ]
[ creature clicking ]
[ growls ]
[ creature clicking , growling ]
[ creature clicking ]
[ growling , clicking ]
[ growls ]
[ rain pattering ]
[ growling ]
[ door squeaks ]
[ snarls ]
[ creature clicking , growling ]
[ groaning ]
[ creature growling ]
[ feedback ]
- [ feedback continues ] - [ growling ]
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ Beyond the sea ♪
♪ Somewhere waiting for me ♪
♪ My lover stands On golden sand ♪
♪ And watches the ships That go sailin ' ♪
- [ baby cries ] - [ panting ]
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ Beyond the sea ♪
[ screaming ]
♪ She 's there watching for me ♪
[ growling ]
♪ If I could fly like birds ♪
[ music ends ]
[ feedback ]
[ squealing ]
[ groaning ]
[ panting ]
[ feedback continues ]
[ squealing ]
[ squealing , growling ]
[ screaming ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ feedback ]